Color is an important tool in designing visualizations.
颜色是可视化设计中一个重要工具
It allows you to encode another variable or split your data into groups.
你可以用颜色对变量进行编码或把数据分组
However, there are a lot of issues you need to
然而 你需要考虑很多问题
consider when choosing which colors to use and how to apply them.
以便选择使用哪些颜色以及如何使用
As an example of the power of color,
为说明颜色的功能
consider these two plots of GDP versus life expectancy.
我们可以分析 GDP 与预期寿命这两个图 作为例子
Look how much more information adding color provided.
看一看添加颜色后如何提供更多信息
We got the idea that higher GDPs correlate with higher life expectancy, however,
我们的结论是更高的 GDP 对应更长的预期寿命
by adding color, the region of the countries belong to is now more apparent.
然而 添加颜色后 国家所属的地区现在变得更有表观性
We can see how the countries are distributed in the world in this plot.
本图中 我们能够看到世界各国的分布图
The low GDP countries are almost all in sub-saharan Africa.
几乎所有低 GDP 国家都位于非洲撒哈拉以南地区
And on the high end,
高 GDP 国家
you see Europe and North America.
包括欧洲和北美
The orange in between is the former Soviet states.
位于两者之间的橙色为前苏联国家
Color is an important tool in visualizations,
颜色是可视化的一项重要工具
and it's important to use it appropriately to have the largest impact.
重要的是适当地使用颜色以最大限度地影响结果
Consider this bar chart.
观察这个柱状图
Overall, I would say that color distracts from the data.
我要说的是 整体而言 颜色导致我们观察数据时分心
The colors shown don't appear to be chosen for any particular reason.
选择的颜色看起来有点随心所欲 没有针对性
In fact, they're are actually the default for
实际上 这些颜色是软件
the software in which this plot was built, rainbow colors.
在生成该图时的默认颜色 即彩虹色
These colors are also quite bright which strains the eyes.
这些颜色也非常鲜艳 有点刺眼
Above all, each color doesn't actually convey any additional information about the data.
尤其是 每个颜色事实上不能传递关于数据的额外信息
The labels on the left side of the bar plot are enough to
柱状图左侧的标签已足以显示
indicate which bar belongs to which type of diamonds cut.
哪一个条形属于哪一种钻石切割
This actually makes the use of color redundant since
实际上 这对于颜色使用而言已经足够
both the labels and the color are indicating the cut type.
因为标签和颜色揭示了切割类型
You might also have noticed that the legend at the right is unnecessary.
你或许也注意到了右侧的图例没有必要
We could simply design this visualization with the labels at the left of the graph,
我们可以使用图形左侧的这些标签设计这一可视化
decreasing the amount of time
这减少了读者阅读时间
the reader's eye jump between the wedge in and the main data display.
眼睛在楔形与主要数据展示之间跳来跳去的时间
Here are my three main tips for using color and plot.
关于颜色和图形的使用 我主要提示三点
My first piece of advice comes from the design field.
我的第一个建议是关于设计字段的
Get it right in black and white.
把该字段设置成黑白色
Before you begin adding color to your data visualization,
开始把颜色添加到数据可视化前
you should determine if you need color in the first place.
你首先要确定你是不是有必要添加颜色
Many times, black, white and shades of
许多情况下 黑色、白色以及灰色阴影
grey will be enough to effectively convey your information.
将足以有效地传递你的信息
Secondly, if you are going to use color,
第二 如果你打算使用颜色
consider using less intense colors such as natural colors or pastels.
要注意尽可能少使用鲜艳的颜色 例如天然色或淡色
You can also add some gray value to bright colors to make them less vibrant.
你也可以为鲜艳的颜色设置灰度值 使颜色看起来更柔和
Colors with higher gray values have
灰度值高的颜色
a softer feel and the eye can concentrate on them for longer periods of time.
感觉更柔和 使得眼睛能够更长时间集中到这些颜色上
Rainbow colors, primary colors and
彩虹色、原色以及
other bright bold colors create noisy visualizations that strain the eye.
其他鲜艳的亮色导致可视化有噪点 也刺激眼睛
My final tip is to make color selections that facilitate communication.
最后 我建议颜色的选择要方便传播
In this example, I used a complimentary color to
在本例中 我使用了互补色
draw attention to the count of ideal cut diamonds.
以使读者注意理想的钻石切割数量
You could use a similar strategy if you
想要在一个图形中突出特定的数据点
want to highlight particular data points in a graphic.
你也可以采用类似的策略
Perhaps you've come across
你可能已经遇到过
some good and not so good examples of color use in visualizations.
可视化中一些有关颜色使用的好案例或不太好的案例
Color can be a tricky component of a visualization but can also encode data,
颜色是可视化中一个棘手的因素 但是 颜色也可以实现数据编码
lead the eye, and help viewers see the most important information of a graphic.
引起关注并帮助读者注意到图形中最重要的信息